<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Analytics</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Data Analytics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Altran</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Meteorites (1)</title>
      <link>/2018/02/12/meteorites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/12/meteorites/</guid>
      <description>GitHub The code for the herein described process can also be freely downloaded from https://github.com/majvdvel/meteorites.
 Meteorite sightings NASA has opened their database to the world at https://data.nasa.gov/, where they demonstrate their own test data and various measurements around the globe. One of the available datasets (which can be downloaded from this location) contains data on over 45 000 meteorites, including their chemical composition, their mass, and the year they were discovered and the corresponding location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About us!</title>
      <link>/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/about/</guid>
      <description>About Altran As a global leader in Engineering and R&amp;amp;D services (ER&amp;amp;D), Altran offers its clients a new way to innovate by developing the products and services of tomorrow. Altran works alongside its clients on every link in the value chain of their project, from conception to industrialization. For over thirty years, the Altran Group has provided its expertise to key players in the Aerospace, Automotive, Defence, Energy, Finance, Life Sciences, Railway, and Telecoms sectors, among others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viewing and analysing GPS traces with R</title>
      <link>/2018/01/10/taxi_traces/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/10/taxi_traces/</guid>
      <description>Viewing and analysing GPS traces with R Nowadays most car drivers use GPS services to reach their destinations. Often this is done via a mobile phone, but soon connected cars will be the norm. As a consequence, the amount of geo-positional data of car trips is continuously increasing. In this blog post I will illustrate how we can use R to analyse and visualise GPS traces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating maps with R and OpenStreetMap (2)</title>
      <link>/2017/11/09/2017-11-09-creating-maps-with-coastlines/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/09/2017-11-09-creating-maps-with-coastlines/</guid>
      <description>GitHub The code for the herein described process can also be freely downloaded from https://github.com/fzenoni/coast-map.
 Where were we In the previous post (click here if you missed it), we managed to put together a relatively short chunk of code that generated the following rather nice map of Brussels Region, which includes all of its 19 municipalities.
 A new challenger appears In that post, we discussed how a certain amount of challenges were overcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating maps with R and OpenStreetMap (1)</title>
      <link>/2017/10/10/2017-10-10-creating-maps-with-r-and-openstreetmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/10/2017-10-10-creating-maps-with-r-and-openstreetmap/</guid>
      <description>GitHub The code for the herein described process can also be freely downloaded from https://github.com/fzenoni/bcr-map.
 Drawing maps with R In the last few years the R community has done big steps in providing friendly tools to manipulate tables extended by geographical information. The need to display such information in a simple way, coupled with the prescriptions of tidy data summarized by Hadley Wickham (https://www.jstatsoft.org/article/view/v059i10) led to the development of R packages such as sf and tmap, as well as considerable improvement of the well-known R graphic library, ggplot2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/page/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/contact/</guid>
      <description>Contact Work in progress, stay tuned!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My awesome project</title>
      <link>/project/my-awesome-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/my-awesome-project/</guid>
      <description>About project Aenean ipsum justo, semper eu nisl ut, pretium tincidunt sem. Praesent et diam sit amet lacus lobortis dictum a id lacus. Quisque hendrerit sit amet turpis eu varius. Ut id lorem ac felis ultrices tincidunt. Pellentesque consequat arcu ac fringilla imperdiet. Phasellus pellentesque, sapien non pulvinar blandit, sapien ante aliquet felis, vel porttitor sapien ante in lacus. Fusce non urna aliquet, malesuada nibh vel, luctus urna. Phasellus ut lacus molestie, varius purus quis, malesuada lorem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>