<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Altran ISY Data Analytics</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Altran ISY Data Analytics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Florian Zenoni</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating maps with R and OpenStreetMap (2)</title>
      <link>/2017/11/09/2017-11-09-creating-maps-with-coastlines/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/09/2017-11-09-creating-maps-with-coastlines/</guid>
      <description>GitHub The code for the herein described process can also be freely downloaded from https://github.com/fzenoni/coast-map.
 Where were we In the previous post (click here if you missed it), we managed to put together a relatively short chunk of code that generated the following rather nice map of Brussels Region, which includes all of its 19 municipalities.
 A new challenger appears In that post, we discussed how a certain amount of challenges were overcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating maps with R and OpenStreetMap (1)</title>
      <link>/2017/10/10/2017-10-10-creating-maps-with-r-and-openstreetmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/10/2017-10-10-creating-maps-with-r-and-openstreetmap/</guid>
      <description>GitHub The code for the herein described process can also be freely downloaded from https://github.com/fzenoni/bcr-map.
 Drawing maps with R In the last few years the R community has done big steps in providing friendly tools to manipulate tables extended by geographical information. The need to display such information in a simple way, coupled with the prescriptions of tidy data summarized by Hadley Wickham (https://www.jstatsoft.org/article/view/v059i10) led to the development of R packages such as sf and tmap, as well as considerable improvement of the well-known R graphic library, ggplot2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/about/</guid>
      <description>About us The Data Analytics team is part of the Altran Belux Intelligent Systems (ISY) division, and provides engineering services to several customers in Belgium. Our academic background is in engineering and/or physical sciences, and our job is all about making sense out of data. We&amp;rsquo;re spread between Brussels and Ghent (and sometimes Leuven).
Altran Altran Technologies is an innovation an engineering consulting firm. We operate in high technology in a variety of domains, from life sciences to mechanical engineering, from the energy to the transportation sector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/page/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/contact/</guid>
      <description>Contact If you have questions or suggestions you can contact our team leader Catalin Lupu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My awesome project</title>
      <link>/project/my-awesome-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/my-awesome-project/</guid>
      <description>About project Aenean ipsum justo, semper eu nisl ut, pretium tincidunt sem. Praesent et diam sit amet lacus lobortis dictum a id lacus. Quisque hendrerit sit amet turpis eu varius. Ut id lorem ac felis ultrices tincidunt. Pellentesque consequat arcu ac fringilla imperdiet. Phasellus pellentesque, sapien non pulvinar blandit, sapien ante aliquet felis, vel porttitor sapien ante in lacus. Fusce non urna aliquet, malesuada nibh vel, luctus urna. Phasellus ut lacus molestie, varius purus quis, malesuada lorem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>