<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sf on Data Analytics</title>
    <link>/tags/sf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sf on Data Analytics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Florian Zenoni</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/sf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Viewing and analysing GPS traces with R</title>
      <link>/2018/01/10/taxi_traces/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/10/taxi_traces/</guid>
      <description>Viewing and analysing GPS traces with RNowadays most car drivers use GPS services to reach their destinations. Often this is done via a mobile phone, but soon connected cars will be the norm. As a consequence, the amount of geo-positional data of car trips is continuously increasing. In this blog post I will illustrate how we can use R to analyse and visualise GPS traces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating maps with R and OpenStreetMap (2)</title>
      <link>/2017/11/09/2017-11-09-creating-maps-with-coastlines/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/11/09/2017-11-09-creating-maps-with-coastlines/</guid>
      <description>GitHubThe code for the herein described process can also be freely downloaded from https://github.com/fzenoni/coast-map.
Where were weIn the previous post (click here if you missed it), we managed to put together a relatively short chunk of code that generated the following rather nice map of Brussels Region, which includes all of its 19 municipalities.
A new challenger appearsIn that post, we discussed how a certain amount of challenges were overcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating maps with R and OpenStreetMap (1)</title>
      <link>/2017/10/10/2017-10-10-creating-maps-with-r-and-openstreetmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/10/10/2017-10-10-creating-maps-with-r-and-openstreetmap/</guid>
      <description>GitHubThe code for the herein described process can also be freely downloaded from https://github.com/fzenoni/bcr-map.
Drawing maps with RIn the last few years the R community has done big steps in providing friendly tools to manipulate tables extended by geographical information. The need to display such information in a simple way, coupled with the prescriptions of tidy data summarized by Hadley Wickham (https://www.jstatsoft.org/article/view/v059i10) led to the development of R packages such as sf and tmap, as well as considerable improvement of the well-known R graphic library, ggplot2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>