<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Data Analytics</title>
    <link>/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Data Analytics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Altran Belgium</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About us!</title>
      <link>/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;about-altran-group-and-altran-belgium&#34;&gt;About Altran Group and Altran Belgium&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a global leader in Engineering and R&amp;amp;D services (ER&amp;amp;D), Altran offers its clients a new way to innovate by developing the products and services of tomorrow. Altran works alongside its clients on every link in the value chain of their project, from conception to industrialization. For over thirty years, the Altran Group has provided its expertise to key players in the Aerospace, Automotive, Defence, Energy, Finance, Life Sciences, Railway, and Telecoms sectors, among others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-intelligent-systems-and-data-analytics&#34;&gt;About Intelligent Systems and Data Analytics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intelligent systems are a new wave of embedded and real-time systems that are highly connected, with massive processing power and performing complex applications. Their pervasiveness is reshaping the real world and how we interact with our digital life. These intelligent systems are creating new opportunities for industry and business, and new experiences for users and consumers. They can be found in all domains, where Altran is a Belgian and global leader in the Engineering R&amp;amp;D market: automotive, rail, aerospace, energy, healthcare, telecoms and consumer electronics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking about the Data Analytics team, our academic background is in engineering and/or physical sciences, and our job is all about making sense out of data. We&amp;rsquo;re spread between Brussels and Ghent (and sometimes Leuven).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We created this blog in the attempt to give back some of the passion and love we got from the online community in all these years.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/page/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/contact/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;contact&#34;&gt;Contact&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work in progress, stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;form action=&#34;https://api.formferret.com/v1/f/YOUR_UNIQUE_FORM_ID&#34;
      method=&#34;POST&#34;
      accept-charset=&#34;UTF-8&#34;&gt;
  
  &lt;input name=&#34;_gotcha&#34; type=&#34;text&#34; /&gt;
  
  &lt;input name=&#34;email&#34; type=&#34;email&#34; placeholder=&#34;you@domain.com&#34;/&gt;
  
  &lt;button type=&#34;submit&#34;&gt;Submit&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>